Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Caricatures and Cartoons 1643, 1756-1943, 1977 PR 10
New-York Historical Society
- Series VII. Undetermined Dates, 19th century-20th century
  - No title. [Croker/Tammany and McLaughlin/Brooklyn Ring], circa 1900? (Folder FF-152)
    Pen and ink drawing. By F. Opper. Acquisition: Purchase, June 28, 1961, Wilbur Fund
  - No title. [A man wielding ax in crowd of mostly women and children on shpboard], circa 1900? (Folder FF-153)
    Drawing. Signed Mo Flabert. Acquisition(?) date on back: June 16, 1927.
  - Why They Stick. Komrad's I again gloryfy in coveying to you of our wonderful achievements which me and Gott has led you to. That you may enjoy Kultur to the end. [German chemical warfare], 1910s? (Folder FF-153)
    Drawing. Signed R.M.S.
  - Getting Another Golden Egg [League of Nations], 1910s? (Folder FF-153)
    Drawing. Signed by Lute Pease. On back [in pencil] "Purchase, April 1981".
  - No title. [Man (Sydney Rosenfeld) dressed in dress and bonnet, holding out bag of money labelled "Subscribers" "Contributors" to female figure dressed in toga labelled "Century Theater". On other side, male figure in toga, arms crossed, labelled "Nat'l Arts Theater".], 1910s? (Folder FF-153)
    Drawing. Signed PAL. On back [in blue pencil] "The Leap Year Theatrical Proposal Mr. Sydney Rosenfeld as the shy damsel. The National Arts Theater as the jilted lover. The Century Theater as the sought lover." Acquisition(?) date on back: Feb. 2, 1921.
  - No title. [Man and cat viewed from below.], 1920s? (Folder FF-153)
    Drawing. Signed by Hy-Mayer. Stamped on back: "Samuel T. Shaw Memorial Collection 1948".
  - No title. [Man dressed in colonial garb holding a skunk.], 1920s? (Folder FF-153)
    Drawing. [In pencil] Rough Sketch.
  - Portrait of man [Franklin D. Roosevelt?] with devils on shoulders., 1930s? (Folder FF-153)
    Colored drawing. Unsigned. Acquisition(?) date on back: March 17, 1952.
  - Above: Uncle "Chew" Wilson (2 Quid Man) and the Campaign Cigar. Below: Toonerville Folks., 1950s? (Folder FF-153)
    Drawing. Signed F. Fox. Inscribed on front: "To Mr. J.A. Voice with compliments of Fontaine Fox".
  - A Historical Landmark Will Be Erected on This Site, 1960s? (Folder FF-153)
    Signed, illegible. New Yorker-type cartoon.
  - "Be gentle with it, men. It's a historic landmark." [Destruction of historic buildings], 1970s? (Folder FF-151)
    Pen and ink drawing by Edward Koren.